Guide to the Cornell athletics records, 1874-2013
Cornell athletics records, 1874-2013
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell athletics records, 1874-2013.
40-1-370
Cornell University.
3.6 cubic feet.
Programs, photographs, advertisements, clippings, reports, and a certificate.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Athletic event programs, photographs, annual reports, advertisements, plaques, cups, films and clippings concerning various Cornell athletic events, including women's athletics, and a certificate of incorporation of the Cornell Athletic Association.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Athletic event programs, photographs, annual reports, advertisements, plaques, cups, films and clippings concerning various Cornell athletic events, including women's athletics, and a certificate of incorporation of the Cornell Athletic Association. Also Cornell Victorious, the Cornell Campaign for Athletics, ca. 1990, V-790; Design plans for the Bartels Hall (formerly Alberding Field House), V-6028; Illini Reflections, ca. 1990 overview of past University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign events and life as presented by past university alumni. Included are Judi Ford-Johnson '73, Roger Ebert '64, Roger Plummer '84, Lester Leutwiler '29, Tom Haller '58, Ray Nitschke '58, and Dick Butkus '64, V-6029. Films include: Here We Are Again, 2 copies, ca. 1985, film about the history of Cornell athletics, F-478, 479; Stanford Today, 1985, film about Stanford University and its athletic programs, F-480. Also slides from the 1974 Cornell and Cornellians presentation by Laurence Koplik.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University--Athletics.; Cornell University--Sports.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Periodicals.; Cornell University. Cornell Athletic Association.
Subjects:
Women college students.; Women athletics.; Athletics--study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Related collections: Football Miscellany, 37-5-3981; Crew Records, 40-1-924; Hockey Films and Ephemera Collection, 40-4-3590; Football motion pictures, 40-2-2205; Track And Field Collection, 40-9-1820.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Sports Programs and Team Booklets
Boxes 1-4, 7, 9, 10
Series II. Reports and Handbooks
Boxes 5, 6
Series III. Notes, Memos, and Brochures
Box 6
Series IV. Articles and Clippings
Boxes 5, 6, 8
Series V. Correspondence
Box 6
Series VI. Budget
Box 6
Series VII. Movie Films, Videos and other media
Box 9
Series VIII. Plaques and cups
Museum items (MU)
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Sports Programs and Team Booklets
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1878-1899 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1900-1909 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1910-1919 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Includes Constitution and By-Laws of the Cornell University Athletic Association, 1916
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1924-1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Includes Rules and Regulations Governing Athletics In Cornell University, issued by the Council on Physical Education and Athletics, 1939.
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Programs, Miscellany (2), 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Programs, Miscellany (3), 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Programs, Miscellany (4), 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Programs, Miscellany, 1979-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Includes Athletics Hall of Fame Induction Ceremony programs 1979-1984
  - Programs, Miscellany (2), 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Programs, Miscellany (3), 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Programs, Miscellany (4), 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Athletics, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Baseball, Softball, 1891, 1986, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Includes an envelope to L.C. Jackson from the Cornell B.B. Association, R.C. McCormick manager, January 30, 1891.
  - Baseball, 2000, 2007, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Baseball, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Baseball, 2005; 2008 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Basketball, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Basketball-Men's, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Basketball Men's, 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Basketball Men's, 2003-2005 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Basketball Men's, 2005-2007, 2007-2008 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Basketball Men's, with ticket stubs, 2008-2013 (Box 10)
  - Basketball Women's, 2001-2004 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Basketball Women's, 2004-2006 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Basketball Women's, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Basketball Women's, 2006, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Crew, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Crew, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Crew, 2004-2006; 2007-2008 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Crew, 2001, 2007, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Cross Country/Track (Box 4, Folder 6)
    -includes 1911-1914, 1990-1992, 1994-1999
  - Cross Country/Track, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Cross Country/Track, 2004-2006 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Cross Country/Track, 2006-2007 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Cross Country/Track, 2007-2009 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Fencing, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fencing, 2006-2007 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Fencing, 2001, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Field Hockey, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Field Hockey, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Field Hockey, 2002-2005 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Field Hockey, 2006, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Football (Box 10)
    -includes November 1916, October 1930, War time imagery October 1942 (including at Syracuse game), 1943, 1946 (Thanksgiving game), 1952, 1965, 1968, 1979
  - Football, 1982, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Football (2), 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Football, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Football, 2002; 2003 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Football, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Football, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Football, 2006; 2008 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Sprint Football, 1990-1999, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sprint Football, 2002-2005 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Gymnastics, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Gymnastics, 2002-2005 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Gymnastics, 2006; 2007 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - SGymnastics, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Ice Hockey-Men's, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ice Hockey Men's, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Ice Hockey, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Ice Hockey-Men's, 2005-2007 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Ice Hockey-Men's, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Ice Hockey-Women's, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ice Hockey-Women's, 2001, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Ice Hockey-Women's, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Ice Hockey-Women's, 2004-2006 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Ice Hockey-Women's, 2006-2007 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Ice Hockey-Women's, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Lacrosse, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lacrosse-Men's, 2001,2006,2009 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Lacrosse-Men's, 2003; 2005 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Lacrosse-Men's, 2007; 2008 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Lacrosse-Women's, 2003; 2004 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Lacrosse-Women's, 2005; 2007; 2008 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Lacrosse-Women's, 2000, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Sailing, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Soccer, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Soccer-Men's, 2002; 2003 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Soccer-Men's, 2004-2006; 2007 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Soccer-Men's, 2006-2009 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Soccer-Men's, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Soccer-Men's, with ticket stubs, 2011-2012 (Box 10)
  - Soccer-Women's, 2002-2005 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Soccer Women's, 2007; 2008 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Softball, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Softball, 2003; 2004 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Softball, 2005; 2008 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Softball, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Squash, 1994-1996, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Swimming, 1990s, 2001, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Swimming and Diving Men's, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Swimming and Diving Women's, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Swimming and Diving Men and Women, 2003-2005 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Tennis, 1990-1999, 2001-2009 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Tennis-Men's, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Tennis-Women's, 2003-2005 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Tennis-Women's, 2006-2007 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Volleyball, 1990, 1994-1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Volleyball, 2002-2005 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Volleyball, 2006,2008 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Wrestling, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Wrestling (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Includes 1990-1991, 1995-1997, 2008-2009
  - Wrestling, 2004-2006 (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Series II. Reports
  - Reports on Athletics, 1946-1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Archery, 1936-1954 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Badminton, 1937-1946 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Canoeing, 1958-1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Field Hockey, 1929-1942 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Folk and Square Dancing, 1940-1953 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Fundamentals, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Interclass Basketball, 1928-1942 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Intramural Basketball, 1929-1948 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Intramural Softball, 1929-1948 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Outing and Games(1946), 1939-1946 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Soccer, 1929-1950 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Swimming, 1929-1950 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Activity Reports: (Womens) Tennis, 1931-1953 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Annual Reports: Physical Education for Women, 1931-1944 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Annual Reports: Physical Education for Women, 1944-1952 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Annual Reports: Physical Education for Women, 1952-1957 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Annual Reports: Physical Education for Women, 1958-1968 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Annual Reports: Physical Education for Women, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Annual Reports: Physical Education for Women, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Annual Reports: Physical Education for Women, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Annual Reports: Physical Education for Women, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Annual Reports: Physical Education for Women, 1977-1981 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Women's Cross Country: Summery of 1976 Season (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Inter Collegiate: Women's Sports, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Field Hockey Association, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Field Hockey: Conference, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Recreation Leadership, 1941-1944 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Organization and Administration of the Dept. of Physical Education for Women, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Physical Education: Athletics Subcommittee-Senate Minutes, 1975-76 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Biannual Report of the Sports Advisory Committee to the Dept. Of P.E. and Athletics, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Sports Advisory Council Newsletter, February 1977 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Report of the Trustee Ad Hoc Committee on Athletics, September 1975 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Minority Report of the Trustee Ad Hoc Committee on Athletics, Judith Younger, September 1975 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Fincancial Developement Plan for Physical Education and Athletics: Cornell, 1983(?) (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - W.A.A. Award Proposal and Cornell Women's SPorts Newsletter, 1976, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Events and Memorable Experiences by F.R. Newman and Articles From The Allied Private, August 1943 (Box 6)
  - Department of Athletics and Physical Education Team Faculty Advisor Handbook, ca. 1997 (Box 10)
  - Department of Athletics and Physical Education Student-Athlete Handbook, ca. 1997 (Box 10)
- Series III. Notes, Memos, and Brochures
  - Women's Ice Hockey: Photo, Memo, Newspaper Clipping, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Women's Ski Team and Tennis Team Photos, 1975, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Women's Fencing, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Wearers of the "C" Winners, 1950-1966 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Women's Sports Brochures, 1974-1976, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Women's Athletic Association Council Brochure, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Fundraising: Women's Athletics, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Title IX: Articles and Memos, 1970-1979 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Title IX: Articles and Memos, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Title IX: Articles and Memos, 1960-1998 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Series IV. Articles and Clippings
  - Early newspaper clippings, Miscellany, 1874-1923 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: Women's Athletics, 1940-1949 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Publications, 1932 and 1927 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Clippings: Women's Basketball, 2008 (Box 8)
  - Clippings: Men's Basketball - Sweet Sixteen, 2010 (Box 8)
- Series V. Correspondence
  - Correspondence: Dedication of Helen Newman Hall, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Deactivation of Women's Athletic Association, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: Martha Arnett (Speaker at "Class of 1927" Banquet), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Series VI. Budget
  - Budget, 1970-1977 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Budget, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Series VII. Movie Films, Videos and other media
  - Slides for Cornellians and Cornell presentation, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Slide show made as part of a presentation by Laurence Koplik '72 and the Cornell Office of Public Information, visual Services and Radio-TV Film. Dedicated to Morris Bishop. Features many photos of various student activities on campus, but particularly athletic teams and coaches.
  - Two photo albums showing renovation of Schoellkopf field, crescent bleachers, press box, Hoy field and Alumni fields., ca. 1988 (Box 9)
  - Binder of slides showing Athletic Facilities Study ca. 1983, shows maps of various Cornell athletics facilities and proposals for future expansion. (Box 9)
  - Cornell Victorious, the Cornell Campaign for Athletics [VHS], ca. 1990; V-790 (Box 9)
  - Design plans for the Bartels Hall (formerly Alberding Field House) [VHS], ca. 1988; V-6028 (Box 9)
  - Illini Reflections [VHS], ca. 1990; V-6029 (Box 9)
    Overview of past University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign events and life as presented by past university alumni. Included are Judi Ford-Johnson '73, Roger Ebert '64, Roger Plummer '84, Lester Leutwiler '29, Tom Haller '58, Ray Nitschke '58, and Dick Butkus '64.
  - Cornell Soccer game [16mm], ca. 1958-1960; F-390 (Box 9)
    Home soccer game on alumni field.
  - Here We Are Again, 2 copies [16mm], ca. 1985; F-478, F-479 (Box 9)
    Film about the history of Cornell athletics.
  - Stanford Today, 1985; F-480 (Box 9)
    Film about Stanford University and its athletic programs.
  - Photos and negatives of inter-college athletic championship banners and plaques, 1910-1916 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Series VIII. Plaques and cups
  - Inter College Cup for Baseball, engraved with winners from 1905 through 1914, 1905-1914; MU-1709
  - Inter College Cup for Soccer, engraved with winners from 1908 through 1913, 1908-1913; MU-1710
  - Inter College Cup for Cross Country, engraved with winners from 1906 through 1914, 1906-1914; MU-1711
  - Inter College Athletic Championship Cross Country plaque, 1914; MU-2061
  - Inter College Athletic Championship Soccer plaque, 1914; MU-2062
  - Inter College Athletic Championship Track plaque, 1915; MU-2063